other investors welcome to business
learnings it has been quite some time
and I've been busy and I was not able to
make any videos for quite some time now
but this video is about
idfc first bank the bank recently
declared its its results for the fourth
quarter of financial year 2020 and the
results are encouraging I have made a
couple of videos on this particular Bank
and I have always been talking very
positive about it and I still positive
for the bank what is going to be the
target price how the bank will perform
in the next coming quarters and the next
few years should you invest in this bank
should you not we will discuss all these
kinds of things in this video so do
watch the video throughout the end to
get a better idea of things okay so just
a quick note that you should always keep
in mind while you are analyzing any kind
of banking stock as few factors net
interest margin the the the fraction of
their loans their loan portfolio I mean
what percentage of loans are given in
what industries or what kind of people
the provisioning the NPA numbers the the
quality of the promoter and and the
current and savings accounts the portion
of that bank let's try to analyze idfc
first bank along these these points and
we will get a better idea of if the bank
is performing good enough or not so
as you all know our idfc first bank is a
merger of capital first and your idfc
bank and the merger happened in
somewhere in September October 2018 so
the first quarterly result of the bank
it was declared in December 2018 and at
that point the bank had 3500 of the of
the loan portfolio the bank had 35
percent retail loans and 65 percent
corporate loans now as of March 20 2015
4 percent of retail loans and 46 percent
of corporate loans their strategy their
vision has been more towards giving out
more of retail loans and reducing their
proportion of corporate loans and they
wanted to do it in the next five years
but you know based on the rate at which
they are converting I don't think this
is going to take five years it's going
to get there they are going to get there
and maybe two years or so two or three
years at most if I do retail loans
matter why do corporate loans are bad by
retail roads are good retail loans are
good because on retail loans banks
typically charge higher interest rates
first second your risk is highly
diversified for a corporate loan if a
particular corporate entity defaults
your entire money is gone right
don't ticket sizes in thousands of
copies one default and thousands of
crores of rupees is gone right for
retail loans even if even if some people
default the the money that's gone out
thats written off is not much these are
two key reasons why if I a retail loan
is preferred over a corporate loan now
in these tough times in coronavirus
times you know normal people people like
us retail people they are also facing a
lot of pressure they are not able to
some of them a lot of them actually are
going to default and that's why retail
as well as corporate loans are under
pressure so coronavirus is going to hit
all of the banks equally hard be the
corporate loan focused bank or be retail
don't focus bank so yes that's an issue
now let's look at the overall loan book
you know if you talk about a lot of
different banks you must have observed
that they focus a lot on growth this
Bank is focused on quality their their
entire loan book size it's not growing
very fast it's not growing in fact it's
had been stagnant the their loan book is
close to 1 lakh crore rupees and they
have not been growing they're just
focusing on converting the corporate
loans to the retailers and the
longer-term retail donuts are going to
get better returns right so a good thing
a positive thing
third is their net interest margin the
net interest margin is you know in in
the very lament terms you pay interest
to the people who deposit money with you
of that you get interest on the loans
that you give out to people the
difference between these two interest
rates is the net interest margin that
sound banks make their money so the net
interest margin of idfc first bank in
December 2018 quarter was 2.9 percent
and now it is four point two four
percent it has been consistently growing
again as I already told you the the
three reason is retail loans there since
they are focusing a lot on retail loans
and retail loans give higher interest
rates that's why the net interest margin
of idfc first bank is improving and it
is bound to improve in the coming few
quarters as well why because their
fraction of retail loans is increasing
okay so the target is five percent again
quite achievable in and not even in five
years but probably in the next two three
years
talk about the the NPA numbers
non-performing asset numbers so gross
and P a 2.6 percent net and P is zero
point nine percent manageable not a very
high number it's quite manageable of
course it's because of the moratorium
impact that people can you know
[Music]
defer their payments of EMIs now let's
talk about Casa current and savings
account
why is casa important for a bank you
know whenever you keep money with your
bank it's either in your savings account
or for businesses in the current account
or you keep them in fixed deposits so
the interest that you get in current
savings account is quite less than the
interests that you get in your fixed
deposits
that's why maintaining of Casa account
is very cheap for a bank more the number
of Casa accounts higher the net interest
margin higher the profitability of the
banks become because they just have to
pay a little money to maintain those
accounts right so the Casa account casts
a percentage of the bank was eight point
six eight percent in December 2018 and
now it is thirty-one point eight seven
as of March twenty twenty you can see a
huge boost and this number is
consistently growing there has not been
a single quarter where this number has
gone down as it has consistently been
increasing and we expect it to increase
in the coming three quarters as well so
net interest margin is surely going to
increase a very good thing and yes
[Music]
okay so yes this was about the Casa
accounts now there was some concern
about the the CA r of the bank the
capital adequacy ratio of the bank which
is currently at thirteen point five
eight percent as of Basel three norms so
the the liquidity of the norms there
were several norms defined several
regulations defined worldwide especially
after the financial crisis of 2008 that
banks have to keep this much amount of
money in pure capital and there were
tears of capital defined so that the
norms are called Basel one Basel - Basel
three norms Basel three is the latest
one and according to Basel three norms
you have to keep about 10.5% as your
capital IQ adequacy ratio think of it as
a money that you keep separate for for
you know if something goes wrong think
of it in that terms in very layman terms
so the capital litigation equity ratio
of this Bank is thirteen point three
eight percent for SDF seats more than
fifteen sixteen percent for IDF C is
just that is it a cause of concern I
think it's not because CID FC first bank
has posted its first quarterly profit
and the retained earnings of these
profits are going to get that into your
your tier 1 capital which will further
improve the capital liquidation so this
number is only going to increase in
future there is no cause of concern
there is no concern at all so don't
worry about this ratio
of course it's well above the regulatory
norms okay so more issues there as well
next yes yes yes okay we've already
talked about the kovaydin pact right you
already talked about the cove in impact
how it's going to impact is going to
impact the retail as well as corporate
borrowers both in similar way and that's
why in the coming few quarters the bank
might Bank might give subdued earnings
provisioning will be higher losses will
be higher but no the management quality
the MD and CEO of this Bank
we were the nothing has an excellent
track record in the long term we
sincerely believe that this going this
Bank is going to perform very well so
yes if you are a long-term investor you
are thinking five ten twenty probably
five ten years down the line then this
Bank is a very good investment as of as
per my opinion as per my research yes in
the next few quarters since this is kind
of a penny stock the stock is well below
twenty rupees for a lot of trading
activity a lot of acute speculation is
bound to happen
a lot of volatility will be seen so it's
a high beta stock and that's why you
know you can see some unexpected down
movements as the as the economic results
for the next few months start coming in
as we see recession we are fearing that
a recession might hit India
and in the next few months the stock
might get hit hard especially the
banking stocks is a part of banking
stalking that's right
problems will be seen but the good thing
is that this bank has a very great
future in it it's going to survive of
course it's not the industry leader but
it is going to survive and it was going
to get a decent amount of market share
so yes please do a research before
therefore investing in this stock this
video was only for educational purpose
post your questions in the comments
below so that I could address I'll
address all of them thanks for watching
this part see you in the next video
tomorrow bye